

Data Scientist

Mail: ykgothi@gmail.com

Phone: +33 758340012

Address: 35000, Rennes, France

github.com/yaswanthkumargothi/Portfolio

linkedin.com/in/yaswanthkumargothireddy

PROFILE

Data & Business analytics graduate with 1+ year experience in Data Analysis, I enjoy solving business challenges by implementing Machine Learning and Deep Learning on large scale text, image, and signal data, and creating value out of structured and unstructured data. I am available for a Full time position as an impactful Data Scientist, making a difference to a business and its environment one algorithm at a time.

SKILLS

Programming

Python, R, SQL, Pyspark

Big Data

HDFS, Apache Hadoop, Airflow

Machine Learning

TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn, Keras, Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib

Data Visualization

Tableau, Gephi, Power BI

Cloud & Version Control

Dataiku, Github, Docker

LANGUAGES

English French Telugu



Yaswanthkumar GOTHIREDDY

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist Intern - Université Gustave Eiffel – IFSTTAR

03/2020 - 08/2020

Nantes, France

- 1. Devised and utilized algorithms and models to mine **big data** stores, perform data and **error analysis** to improve models, and clean and validate data for uniformity and accuracy.
- 2. Programmed Robust Data Pipelines utilizing Data science Techniques such as Cross-validation and optimization. Implemented ensemble models, convolutional Neural Networks using **TensorFlow**, **Python**, and **Scikit-Learn**.
- 3. Provided technical documentation and communicated results to the Team as needed for implementing these approaches in production systems.
- 4. Results: Developed a working wheel classification model with an accuracy of 91% on a noisy sensor data.

Research Data Assistant- Rennes School of Busines

02/2019 - 08/2019

Rennes, France

- 1. Mined 40GB of patent claims text data using **Natural Language Processing** techniques and **Google BigQuery**.
- 2. Created a Data Orchestration pipeline in **Apache Airflow** to rerun queries for 300+ keywords
- 3. Designed and created Database of Patent keywords in **MySQL** from extracted information.

Data Analyst- CSIR-Central Drug Research Institute

08/2017 - 06/2018

Lucknow, India

- 1. Mined data from primary and secondary sources, then reorganizing said data in a format that can be easily utilized by HIV researchers.
- 2. Using **statistical tools** to interpret data sets, paying particular attention to trends and patterns that could be valuable for diagnostic and predictive analytics efforts. Provided Valuable insights to researcher's creating **Dashboards** and Visualizations using **R Shiny**
- 3. Prepared reports for Researchers that effectively communicates trends, patterns, and predictions using relevant data. Collaborated with programmers to identify opportunities for process improvements, recommend system modifications.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Data and Business Analytics

Rennes School of Business

09/2018 - 10/2020

Rennes, France

M.Tech Mechatronics Engineering

National Institute of Technology Karnataka 07/2013 - 07/2015

Surathkal, India

B.Tech Electronics and Communication Engineering

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Kakinada 08/2008 - 05/2012

Kakinada, India

CERTIFICATIONS

TensorFlow Developer Certificate – Accredition : https://bit.ly/31kPycD
Dataiku Core Designer Certificate – Accredition : https://bit.ly/31qpYmx
PGP in BigData Analytics and Optimization, INSOFE, Hyderabad

INTERESTS

Member at Namaste Briezh, Blogging, Bicycling, Travel, Photography